Devlin Booth

Profile: Junior Software Engineer

adevlin.booth@gmail.com (504) 430-6996 • Los Angeles, CA 90046 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/devlin-booth/ GitHub: https://github.com/adevlinb

Motivated, passionate, and dedicated individual with hands-on experience in the software development lifecycle from requirement gathering to project execution. Capable of building fullstack, frontend, or backend applications with modern languages and frameworks such as NodeJS, ExpressJS, React, and JavaScript. Solid commitment to supporting technical design teams with ideas, strategies, and concepts while participating in testing and documentation all under strict project deadlines. Ability to drive continuous improvement of software quality, customer experience, and maintainability of products/features. Excellent communication, analytical, and problem-solving skills, while staying current in the ever-changing affairs in the field of software.

Technical Proficiencies

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Libraries: Mongoose, React, Materialize, Bootstrap, jQuery, Socket.IO

Frameworks: Express.js, Django

Software: Affinity Photo, Affinity Designer, AutoCAD, Adobe Creative Suite

Others: Amazon S3 Cloud Storage, NodeJS

Career Experience

General Assembly - Remote

Dec 2021- Present

Software Engineering Instructional Associate - Pilot Program for Blended Learning (Sep 2022 – Dec 2022)

Software Engineering Instructional Associate (Jun 2022 – Sep 2022)

Perform wide range of duties, such as administering quizzes, introducing assignments, and facilitating student learning of programming languages, frameworks, databases, development patterns, and deployment. Guide students through the rigorous transformational journey to software development apprenticeship. Facilitate a safe, supportive, and energetic environment, welcoming students with diverse needs and learning styles.

- Leveraged strong instructional skills while educating students on programming and Full stack development as software engineering instructor.
- Selected to be one of three Instructional Associates in a pilot program for Blended Learning. This new approach will allow for one-on-one time with each student to facilitate key learning objects more clearly and ensure retention.

Software Engineering Apprenticeship (Dec 2021 - Mar 2022)

Acquired hands-on experience with multiple programming languages, frameworks, libraries, and database types during 420-hour immersive training program, executing app planning via wire-framing, ERD-diagramming, and (AAU) user-story implementation of features for agile web development practices.

Assumed the role of project manager in a three-person team's git-hub workflow environment.

Key Projects:

XYLA - NodeJS, Express, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Google Books API

Devlin Booth

✓ Developed a social app project, allowing users to add books to their library, make recommendations, postings, and comment on other users' posts in the "social wall."

TasteBuds - Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Amazon S3

✓ Full CRUD dining events and recipe-saving app enabling users to create profile, join groups, create events, and recommend their recipes to those events with an option to vote on recipes.

Climate Events - NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Google OAuth

✓ An event logging app and diary, providing weather data based on user-provided address. Events can be accessed through the dashboard's main page, which would be organized based on upcoming dates and also, features a searchable tagging system for users to create, read, update, and delete tags on each event.

Mastermind - JavaScript, HTML, CSS

✓ Simplified coding logic to develop a digital version of the popular 1970s coding game Mastermind. Utilized DOM manipulation and "click" event listeners to gain access to elements, update state, and create winning logic.

Prior Experience as Trainer/Server/Special Events | Avra, TAO Uptown, Dos Caminos - 2011 to 2021

Education

Certificate, Software Engineering Immersive | Mar 2022

General Assembly - Remote

Masters' Degree in Landscape Architecture | 2011

Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge, LA

Bachelors' Degree in Urban Planning | 2007

University of New Orleans - New Orleans, LA

Portfolio

Link: http://devlin-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Languages

English - Expert

Spanish - Intermediate